Simon Hudson

Front-End Developer

hellosimonhudson.com / linkedin.com/in/hellosimonhudson

I am an experienced Front-End Developer who uses HTML, CSS, JavaScript and TypeScript to create accessible and usable websites and applications. I am passionate about web accessibility and how to build for assistive technologies. I'm also a big fan of test-driven development, clean code, and striving for simple solutions to complex problems.

Core skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript/TypeScript, React, Sass, Node.js, Next.js, Express, Styled Components, Jest, Enzyme, React Testing Library, Mocha, Chai, Nightwatch, Cypress, Accessibility/WCAG Guidelines

Experience

Senior Software Engineer – Admiral Group (Nov 2023 – present)

 Working with a globally distributed team on Admiral's Pet Insurance product, using the <u>FintechOS platform</u> to configure and orchestrate all aspects of the proposition, including policies, back-office functions, and user journeys.

Product Developer – Experian (May 2014 – Nov 2023)

- Built and maintained Experian's <u>Marketplace web app</u>, primarily using Node, React and Styled Components.
- Wrote extensive unit tests to meet minimum threshold requirements, which also ensured the AWS-based CI/CD pipeline could run with confidence, allowing multiple releases per day.
- Championed accessibility standards across the entire team. Created suite of automation and unit tests to verify journeys against WCAG 2.1 AA standards. Acted as point-ofcontact for accessibility issues and helped train Developers/QA in common accessibility issues and how to test using assistive technologies.
- Acted as Security Champion for the team. Proactively reviewed scans from tooling such as Veracode and Aguasec. Liaised with Security Champions from other teams.
- As a long-standing member of the team, I acted as a mentor/buddy to new starters and graduates, giving support and feedback where required.

Senior Front-End Developer – 4energy (July 2013 – May 2014)

- Creating monitoring software for data centre cooling systems.
- Migrated existing PHP-based front-end over to use Kendo UI library and Apache Velocity templating language, as well as Sass for CSS.

Front-End Developer – NHS Choices (Capita) (May 2009 – Jul 2013)

- Worked on one of the largest websites in Europe (<u>www.nhs.uk</u>)
- Wrote front-end code to very high standard, and liaised with back-end developers to integrate it into the Sharepoint/.NET solution
- As a government website, it required strict attention to accessibility standards. Had regular audits from external parties such as <u>R.N.I.B</u> and <u>AbilityNet</u>, and would implement updates based on their recommendations.

Senior Web Designer – Manheim Europe (Oct 2006 – May 2009)

- Worked on a range of projects from small banner adverts and HTML e-mails, through to designing and implementing a group-wide intranet based on Drupal CMS.
- Solely responsible for designing and building websites for the company's operations in continental Europe.
- Assisted on digital and print projects for high-profile clients such as BMW, Toyota and Daimler Chrysler.
- Assisted the Design Manager in the running of the department and acted as the main point-of-contact in his absence.

Graphic Designer/Web Developer – University of Derby Students Union (Nov 2004 – Sep 2006)

- Working part-time during my studies, this role offered me the chance to gain real-world experience whilst studying.
- Assisted the lead designer in all aspects of Union marketing, from booklets and posters for events, through to maintenance of the Union website and contributing to the awardwinning monthly student magazine.
- Given the responsibility of re-designing, building and launching the microsite for the Union's satellite campus in Buxton.

Education

University of Derby (2004 – 2006)

Foundation Degree in New Media Design & Production (Pass with Merit)

Derby College (1997 – 1999)

A Level English (Language & Literature), Psychology, Media Studies

Chellaston Secondary School, Derby (1992 – 1997)

9 G.C.S.E Higher Grade passes

References

Available on request